vocuspr.com 2012-05-03

# Vocus Privacy Statement

This is the web site of Vocus, Inc.

Our postal address is:  
12051 Indian Creek Ct.  
Beltsville, MD 20705  
Phone: 301.459.2590

Vocus takes privacy seriously. As a leading provider of on-demand software for corporate communications and public relations, we are committed to establishing and maintaining policies and procedures which protect the privacy of personal information gathered from our customers, prospects and other visitors to our website.

Vocus collects information from our users at several different points on our website to enable us to better inform you about our service. By knowing your preferences we can deliver relevant information that meets your needs and ensure that your visit to our site is quick, easy and productive. Vocus is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this site, you may contact us via email at [privacy@vocus.com](mailto:privacy@vocus.com). In order for Vocus to take the appropriate action please describe in reasonable detail the nature of your request or inquiry.

## Collected Information:

For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes only the consumer's domain name, but not the email address (where possible).

We collect the email addresses of those who communicate with us via email, information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey information and/or site registrations. The information we collect is used by us to contact consumers for marketing purposes, not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes. If you do not want to receive email from us in the future, please unsubscribe [here](http://prsoftware.vocus.com/content/VOCUSUNSUBSCRIBE).

If you are a member of the media and would like to discuss your Vocus database record, please email [mrg@vocus.com](mailto:mrg@vocus.com) and our research team will contact you.

If you supply us with your postal address online you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know by calling us at the number provided above. Please provide us with your exact name and address. We will be sure your name is removed from the list we share with other organizations.

Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers online may receive telephone contact from us with information regarding new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such telephone calls, please let us know by sending us an email at the above address. Please provide us with your name and phone number. We will be sure your name is removed from the list we share with other organizations.

## Cookies:

Vocus may use "cookie" technology to track or record information about our Web site visitors. Vocus requires the use of "cookie" technology so that we can guarantee we'll present the correct information to users as they move from screen to screen. These cookies are "session-specific" and are not used to record personal information, or to associate personal information with the use of the Vocus service. Vocus users who disable their Web browsers' ability to accept cookies will be able to browse our Web site but will not be able to successfully use our service.

## Changes to Personal Information and Opting Out:

Upon request we provide site visitors with access to information that we have collected and that we maintain about them. Upon request we offer visitors the ability to have inaccuracies corrected in contact information. Consumers can have this information corrected by sending us an email at the above address. Customers can also opt out at any time. 

## Third-Party Sites:

The site contains links to other Web sites. Vocus is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these Web sites. Customers and visitors will need to check the policy statement of others' Web sites to understand their policies. Customers and visitors who access a linked site may be disclosing their private information. It is the responsibility of the user to keep such information private and confidential.

## Security:

With respect to security, we employ state-of-the-art technology and security measures in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.

## Changes to Privacy Statement:

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. Vocus will update this policy from time to time. A "last revised" date will always be included on the bottom of the statement. To keep up-to-date with Vocus' policy, please check this page periodically. 

## Contacting the Website:

If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at the above addresses or phone number.

Last revised 11/03/2003 

Vocus, Inc. is committed to protecting the privacy of anyone who uses Vocus' online software. One of the ways in which we demonstrate this commitment is through the care we take to protect the privacy of information which we collect when we host your data on our servers. Vocus owns and manages all of its servers. We typically purchase or lease these servers, which we then install in a state-of-the-art data center operated by Qwest. Vocus selected Qwest based on its ability to provide fast and redundant access to the Internet and world class facilities for Vocus applications. Vocus has entered into binding legal agreements with Qwest, with the objective, among others, of protecting your privacy, and the privacy of the people who use our software.

## Collected Information:

Users' names and email addresses ("Customer Information") are collected and maintained in the Vocus application for purposes of managing the login authentication process, and to allow the application to send notifications to the end user. An example of an application notification would be an email notice informing the user that a scheduled task has been completed.

We promise that we will not give any Customer Information to a third party, unless we are required to do so in order to comply with the law.

If you feel that Vocus is not abiding by this statement, you should contact us by addressing your concerns to [privacy@vocus.com.](mailto:privacy@vocus.com)

## Cookies:

The Vocus application utilizes session specific cookies so that only authenticated users can navigate the application. We also support non-session cookies for allowing the user to automatically remember their login credentials to gain access to the application. If Advanced User Account Security is enabled, then support for non-session cookies is disabled.

## Security:

All hosted environments meet the following physical security requirements - single point of entry to hosting areas; main access monitored with additional access for emergency purposes only; surveillance cameras in facility; access validation with biometric identity check; access only to persons on Vocus' approved access list.

All hosted environments also meet the following electronic security conditions - login validation; creation of accounts only as verified by Vocus; secure SSL (encrypted) connections to access servers; servers running behind secure firewall.

One of the options we offer is Secure Socket Layer (SSL). If you implement our SSL option, we will not transmit Customer Information for the particular user interface that has the SSL over the public internet "in the clear", i.e., without it first being encrypted.

Vocus imposes strict internal controls over those of its employees with access to Customer Information. Such access is granted only on a need to know basis. All hosting administrators are required to undergo criminal and other background checks. 

## Changes to Personal Information:

Our software is configured to enable you to give your end users the means to access their own personal information for the purposes of deleting it, and/or correcting it.

## Changes to Privacy Statement:

Vocus will update this policy from time to time. A "last revised" date will always be included on the bottom of the statement. To keep up-to-date with Vocus' policy, please check this page periodically. 

## Contacting the Website:

If you have any questions about this statement, or our practices as they affect the privacy of hosted data, you can contact us on [privacy@vocus.com.](mailto:privacy@vocus.com)

Last revised 09/30/2003
